<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<dict
	num="219"
	id="219"
	name="219">
	<key>and</key>
	<ps>ænd, ənd, ən</ps>
	<pron>http://res.iciba.com/resource/amp3/0/0/be/5d/be5d5d37542d75f93a87094459f76678.mp3</pron>
	<ps>ənd, ən,ænd</ps>
	<pron>http://res.iciba.com/resource/amp3/1/0/be/5d/be5d5d37542d75f93a87094459f76678.mp3</pron>
	<pos>conj.</pos>
	<acceptation>和，与；而且；于是，然后；因此；
	</acceptation>
	<sent>
		<orig>
			"And", "but"and"whereas" are conjunctions.
		</orig>
		<trans>
			and，but和whereas是连词。
		</trans>
	</sent>
	<sent>
		<orig>
			There is a mass of murkiness which neither moonlight nor sunlight can
			penetrate.; There is gloom above and darkness below, with the rays of
			the sun and the moon completely shut out.;(The cold winds whirled up
			the yellow sands) veiling the earth and the sky in shadows and
			dulling the light of the sun and the moon.
		</orig>
		<trans>
			天昏地暗，日月无光。
		</trans>
	</sent>
	<sent>
		<orig>
			As they grow old, people also accumulate belongings for two other
			reasons, lack of physical and mental energy, both of which are
			essential in turning out and throwing out and throwing away,and
			sentiment.
		</orig>
		<trans>
			当人到老年时，他们还会由于两个原因而积聚东西，其一为缺乏体力和脑力——这两方面的精力在翻出无用的东西并把它们扔掉都是重要的；另一个原因是感情问题。不管是power，force
			还是strength，都离不开食物中的营养所提供的energy。用作技术术语时，strength的意思的“强度”
		</trans>
	</sent>
	<sent>
		<orig>
			It's better to go back and make a net than to stand by the pond and long
			for fish.; Better return home and make a net than long for fish by
			the waterside.; It's better to go back and make a net than to covet
			the fish by merely staring into the water -- one should have a
			down-to-earth style of work to attain one's goal.; One should take
			practical steps to achieve one's aims.
		</orig>
		<trans>
			临渊羡鱼，莫如退而结网。
		</trans>
	</sent>
	<sent>
		<orig>
			The Great Wall of China is the longest and greatest wall in the world.
			Starting from the Shanhaiguan Pass in the east and ending at the
			Jiayuguan Pass in the west, it covers a total length of over 13,400
			li (6,700 kilometres). If the bricks and stones that went into the
			construction of the Great Wall were used to pave a road five metres
			wide and 35 centimetres thick, it would encircle the globe three to
			four times.
		</orig>
		<trans>
			中国的万里长城是世界上最长最伟大的城墙。它东起山海关，西至嘉峪关，全长13400多里。修筑长城的砖石，如果用来铺筑宽5米、厚35厘米的马路，那就能环绕地球三、四周。
		</trans>
	</sent>
</dict>
