<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<dict
	num="219"
	id="219"
	name="219">
	<key>in</key>
	<ps>in</ps>
	<pron>http://res.iciba.com/resource/amp3/0/0/13/b5/13b5bfe96f3e2fe411c9f66f4a582adf.mp3</pron>
	<ps>ɪn</ps>
	<pron>http://res.iciba.com/resource/amp3/1/0/13/b5/13b5bfe96f3e2fe411c9f66f4a582adf.mp3</pron>
	<pos>prep.</pos>
	<acceptation>采用（某种方式）；穿着，带着；（表示位置）在…里面，（表示领域，范围）在…以内；（表示品质、能力等）在…之中；
	</acceptation>
	<pos>adv.</pos>
	<acceptation>在家；进入，到达；流行；当选；
	</acceptation>
	<pos>adj.</pos>
	<acceptation>在内的，朝内的；在位的，执政的；[口语]流行的，时髦的；（车等）到站的；
	</acceptation>
	<pos>n.</pos>
	<acceptation>
		执政党，掌权者；知情者；
		<美口>
			入口，门路；
			<体>（板球或棒球）攻球的一方；
	</acceptation>
	<sent>
		<orig>
			There are a few mistakes in it.
		</orig>
		<trans>
			这里有几个错误。（比较：There are few mistakes in it.这里几乎没有错误。）
		</trans>
	</sent>
	<sent>
		<orig>
			Printing originated in China. In the period between the Sui Dynasty in the
			second half of the 6th century and the Tang Dynasty in the first half
			of the early 7th century, lithographic printing was invented and, in
			the 9th century, a large number of books began to be printed by the
			lithographic process. In the reign of Emperor Qingli of the Northern
			Song Dynasty (960 A.D.-1127 A.D.), a common fellow named Bi Sheng
			invented printing by movable type and started to use baked clay types
			for printing. The technology was introduced to other countries in
			about the mid-8th century.
		</orig>
		<trans>
			中国首先发明印刷术。公元6世纪下半叶到7世纪上半叶的隋、唐之际， 中国就发明了雕版印刷，到9世纪， 开始了大规模的雕版印书。北宋庆历年间， 平民毕升发明用胶泥焙烧的活字，
			开始了活字印刷。约在8世纪中叶，印刷术传到国外。
		</trans>
	</sent>
	<sent>
		<orig>
			"The Deeds of King Gesar," a folk epic of the Tibetan nationality in
			China, is the world's longest epic, comprising 36 volumes in 15
			million words, with one million to 1.5 million lines in poetry alone
			in addition to those in prose. The epic enjoys popularity in areas
			inhabited by people of the Tibetan, Mongolian, and Tu nationalities.
		</orig>
		<trans>
			中国藏族的长篇叙事诗《格萨尔王传》是世界最长的史诗。 除散文 部 分， 仅史诗部分就有100万至150万行， 36部， 1500万字。 史诗流传于藏族、蒙古族、土族等地区。
		</trans>
	</sent>
	<sent>
		<orig>
			Papermaking originated in China in the second century B.C. Paper made from linen
			in the early West Han Dynasty (206 B.C.-24 A.D.) was the world's
			earliest kind of paper made from plant fibres. By pooling the
			expertise of craftsmen in papermaking, Cai Lun of the East Han
			Dynasty (25 A. D.-220 A.D.) succeeded in producing quality paper from
			linen craps, rags, and used fish nets. Papermaking technology was
			introduced to the West in the third century.
		</orig>
		<trans>
			公元前2世纪我国发明纸。 而汉初造的麻纸是世界上现存最早的植物纤维纸。
			东汉蔡伦集中了工匠们的造纸经验，用麻头、破布、旧鱼网作原料，监造出一批良纸。造纸术从3世纪起传到国外。
		</trans>
	</sent>
	<sent>
		<orig>
			China boasts the world's earliest observatory, built in Nanking in 1385 in
			the Ming Dynasty (1368 A.D.-1644 A.D.), three centuries ahead of the
			Greenwich Observatory built in Britain in 1670.
		</orig>
		<trans>
			中国建有世界上最早的气象台。公元1385年， 明朝在南京建立观象台，比英国格林尼治观象台（建于1670年）早三个世纪。
		</trans>
	</sent>
</dict>
