<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<dict
	num="219"
	id="219"
	name="219">
	<key>of</key>
	<ps>ɔv, əv, v, f</ps>
	<pron>http://res-tts.iciba.com/8/b/f/8bf8854bebe108183caeb845c7676ae4.mp3</pron>
	<ps>ʌv, ɑv,əv</ps>
	<pron>http://res.iciba.com/resource/amp3/1/0/8b/f8/8bf8854bebe108183caeb845c7676ae4.mp3</pron>
	<pos>prep.</pos>
	<acceptation>关于；属于…的；由…制成；
	</acceptation>
	<pos>aux.</pos>
	<acceptation>助动词。 [非标准用语、方言] =have [主用于虚拟语气]；
	</acceptation>
	<sent>
		<orig>
			In software engineering, the degree of complication of a system or
			system component, determined by such factors as the number and
			intricacy of interfaces, the number and intricacy of conditional
			branches, the degree of nesting, the types of data structures, and
			other system characteristics.
		</orig>
		<trans>
			在软件工程中，系统或系统组成部分的复杂程度由下述因素确定：接口的数量和错综程度、条件转移的数量和错综程度、嵌套的深度、数据结构的类型，以及其它一些系统特性。
		</trans>
	</sent>
	<sent>
		<orig>
			"The Chronological Record of Historians," written by Sima Qian of the
			Western Han Dynasty (206 B.C.-24 A.D.), was the world's earliest
			biographical work of literature, covering a history of 3,000 years.
			Its contents rang from the legendary Huang Di, or Yellow Emperor, to
			Emperor Wudi of the Han Dynasty (206B.C.-220A.D.).
		</orig>
		<trans>
			中国西汉司马迁编著的《史记》是世界上最早的传记文学。它记事起于传说中的黄帝，迄于汉武帝，首尾3000年。
		</trans>
	</sent>
	<sent>
		<orig>
			China ranks first in the world for the number of species of chrysanthemum.
			Thirty-five varieties of chrysanthemum were recorded in "A Manual of
			Chrysanthemum," written by Liu Meng of the Song Dynasty (960
			A.D.-1279 A.D.), who pointed out that variation led to more
			biological species.
		</orig>
		<trans>
			中国菊花品种居世界第一。公元10世纪时， 宋朝刘蒙所著《菊谱》中指出， 变异可形成生物的新类型，记有35种菊花品种。
		</trans>
	</sent>
	<sent>
		<orig>
			Convinced of the importance of education, modern states "invest"in
			institutions of learning to get back "interest"in the form of a large
			group of enlighted young men and women who are potential leaders.
		</orig>
		<trans>
			现代国家由于确信教育的重要性，才向教育机构“投资”，以期获得一大批有知识的男女青年的形式收回“利息”，这些青年是潜在的领导人。
		</trans>
	</sent>
	<sent>
		<orig>
			Having suffered grievously from biological weapons attacks in the past,
			China supports work that helps comprehensively to strengthen the
			effectiveness of the convention. It has actively participated in the
			work of drawing up a Protocol of the Ad Hoc Group of States Parties
			to the BWC established in 1994, and has made contributions to the
			progress of the negotiations on the Protocol.
		</orig>
		<trans>
			中国在历史上也曾深受生物武器之害。中国支持全面加强《禁止生物武器公约》有效性的工作，积极参加了于1994年设立的公约缔约国特设工作组有关制定《公约》议定书的工作，并为议定书的谈判取得进展作出了贡献。
		</trans>
	</sent>
</dict>
