<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<dict
	num="219"
	id="219"
	name="219">
	<key>by</key>
	<ps>bai</ps>
	<pron>http://res.iciba.com/resource/amp3/0/0/df/3f/df3f079de6961496f0460dcfdbf9bca3.mp3</pron>
	<ps>baɪ</ps>
	<pron>http://res-tts.iciba.com/d/f/3/df3f079de6961496f0460dcfdbf9bca3.mp3</pron>
	<pos>prep.</pos>
	<acceptation>靠，通过；被，由；沿着；按照；
	</acceptation>
	<pos>adv.</pos>
	<acceptation>经过，过去；在侧，在附近；短暂拜访；
	</acceptation>
	<sent>
		<orig>
			"The Star Chart" written by Gan De and "Astronomy" by Shi Shen of the
			Warring States Period (475 B.C.-221 B.C.) were the earliest star
			catalogues in the world. The two star charts presented in the books
			record positions of 120 stars. These positions, recorded 200 years
			earlier than those by other countries, are remarkably accurate, even
			by modern standards.
		</orig>
		<trans>
			中国战国时代甘德著的《星点》和石申著的《天文》是世界上最早的星表。 两表里记有120颗恒星的位置， 至今还非常准确， 比其他国家观测恒星早200多年。
		</trans>
	</sent>
	<sent>
		<orig>
			It's better to go back and make a net than to stand by the pond and long
			for fish.; Better return home and make a net than long for fish by
			the waterside.; It's better to go back and make a net than to covet
			the fish by merely staring into the water -- one should have a
			down-to-earth style of work to attain one's goal.; One should take
			practical steps to achieve one's aims.
		</orig>
		<trans>
			临渊羡鱼，莫如退而结网。
		</trans>
	</sent>
	<sent>
		<orig>
			A good share of the answer rested in the kind of pride that is
			stimulated by the job, by the activity of accomplishing.
		</orig>
		<trans>
			答案很大程度上在于工作和成就所激发出来的那种自豪。
		</trans>
	</sent>
	<sent>
		<orig>
			A sound made by tapping on the hull of a ship will be reflected from
			the sea bottom, and by measuring the time interval between the taps
			and the receipt of the echoes the depth of the sea at that point can
			be calculated.
		</orig>
		<trans>
			在船体上轻轻敲击的声响会从海底反射回来，通过测量敲击和收到回声之间的时间间隔，可以计算出该处海洋的深度。
		</trans>
	</sent>
	<sent>
		<orig>
			Admittedly we can make the journey by train, but there is no harm in our
			travelling by boat.
		</orig>
		<trans>
			乘车固可，乘船亦无不可。
		</trans>
	</sent>
</dict>
